

Curriculum Vitae | Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai | Exp. 18 Years and 05 Months

Educational Qualification:

2008 - Graduate Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical from Institute/University GCE.

2003 - Diploma Technical in Mechanical Engineering from Institute/University GPP.

Professional Qualification:

ASNT NDT Level III - Radiographic Testing (RT) (Valid till 30/06/2022)

ASNT NDT Level III - Ultrasonic Testing (UT) (Valid till 21/08/2022)

Core Competency in Inspection/Assessment of:

Civil Pull Out Test, Civil Slump test, Civil Special Penetrant test, Civil Vertical and lateral test, Plate Load test, Civil Visual Examination, Mechanical Eddy Current test, Mechanical Leak test, Mechanical Magnetic Particle test, Mechanical Vacuum box test, Mechanical Visual Examination

Summary of Expertise:

- Inspection of Static Equipment (Pressure Vessel, Heat Exchanger, Column etc.)
- Bulk Items (Pipes, Fittings, Plates, piping skids etc.)
- Inspection of Line Pipes
- Inspection of 3LPE Coating
- NDT evaluation & Interpretation
- Physical, Chemical

Copyright: This document is the property of TUV India Pvt. Ltd. and should not be reproduced, except in full without the consent of Tuv Pvt. Ltd. TUV India Private Limited (TÜV NORD GROUP): (REGD. & HEAD OFFICE),

801, Raheja Plaza - I, LBS Marg, Ghatkopar (West), Mumbai - 400086, Maharashtra, India. Tel: + 91 22 66477000, Email: inspection@tuv-nord.com; Website: www.tuv-nord.com/in.

Form No: F /MR/ 42/ CV/ INSP/ Rev.2; Revision Date: 01:02:2024



Curriculum Vitae | Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai | Exp. 18 Years and 05 Months

Work Experience:

Period : 01/04/2021 to Till Date
Employer Name : TUV India Private Limited

Location : MUMBAI

Designation : Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai

Responsibilities : • Ensuring IMS compliance.

Process attributes measurement and control for continuous improvement.

• Handling customer complaints.

• Involved in Development of process tool.

• Conducting IMS internal audits.

 Representative for External Accreditation and certification audits, PSU Empanelment audits.

· Conducting QMS and safety induction training.

Period : 01/07/2018 to 31/03/2021
Employer Name : TUV India Private Limited

Location : Mumbai

Designation: Senior Engineer QA

Responsibilities : • Responsi

- : Responsible for implementation, monitoring of ISO 9001, ISO 17020 systems and facilitating the requirement of External Quality System Audits at Mumbai branch division.
 - Planning, preparing Internal audits for Inspection Services at PC in Coordination with Corporate QA.
 - Reporting the performance of the Quality System in accordance to ISO 9001, ISO 17020 to Corporate QA.
 - Ensuring that the requirement and improvements of Quality System as described in the manual, audits and associated documents are maintained and fully implemented.
 - Preparation of project quality plans, procedures and work instruction based on client input.
 - · Conduct vendor assessment on behalf of clients.
 - Stewarding compliance to HSE requirements within the organization & mp; at work sites.
 - Documenting All Customer Complaints at PC level and forwarding it to corporate QA and ensuring proper timely reply and corrective actions.
 - Ensuring effective monitoring (on-site & Defensite) through onsite monitoring calendar, scheduling surprise visits and conducting monitoring (On-site / Off-site) on selected cases.
 - Monitoring Training as per Calendar, induction Training of New Joiners, Quizzes at PC level and ensuring its effectiveness in coordination with corporate QA, getting Training modules prepared.
 - Currently responsible for QA activities like implementation and monitoring of ISO 9001 & D17020 standards.
 - Notifying corporate QA for PC level Update of QA documentation System & Documentation System & Standards on Share Portal / Server.

Copyright: This document is the property of TUV India Pvt. Ltd. and should not be reproduced, except in full without the consent of Tuv Pvt. Ltd.
TUV India Private Limited (TÜV NORD GROUP): (REGD. & HEAD OFFICE),

101 Policy Disease (New York) Mymphia Disease (New York) Mymphia Disease (New York)



Curriculum Vitae | Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai | Exp. 18 Years and 05 Months

- Ensuring circulation of Technical Circulars to concerns within PC.
- Monitor competence evaluation and up gradation and assignment at PC level.
- Any other QA activity assigned by PC head or requested by Corporate QA – Inspection Services.
- Conducting Vendor evaluation and factory capability assessments audits.
- Conducting induction training for new joinee's.

Period : 01/07/2011 to 30/06/2018
Employer Name : TUV India Private Limited

Location : Mumbai

Designation: Inspection Engineer

Responsibilities: • Approved inspector for NPCIL (Nuclear Power Corporation India Limited) for their L & T Power - RAPP 7 & 8 Nuclear Project

- Carrying out inspection as per Inspection Test Plan, QC Procedures, and Specifications & International Codes for Raw materials such as Pipe, tubes, valves, fittings etc. and Various Equipment's such as pressure Vessel, Tanks etc.
- Inspection of centrifugal pumps.
- Coordinating with Client, Vendor & Team members for inspection related activities.
- Inspection of CS, LAS, SS pipes at mill & stockists in India.
- Inspection of API 5L bare or 3LPE line pipes at source.
- Inspection of CS, LTCS, LAS, SS forged fittings as per ASME B 16.11 & butt welding fittings like LR & SR elbows, Equal & Unequal Tee's, Concentric & eccentric reducers, pipe nipples as per ASME B 16.9.
- Inspection of Branch outlet fittings as per MSS SP 97.
- CS, SS & LAS Flanges as per ASME B 16.5 & 16.47 at source.
- Inspection of CS, SS, LAS plates at mill & stockists ware house.
- Witnessing mechanical tests on materials and welds at NABL & non NABL laboratories.
- Approval of QAP as per PR/MR.
- Preparation of Daily Visit Reports & Inspection Release Notes.
- Coordinating with Client, Vendor & Team members for inspection related activities.
- Review / enhancement of QAP /ITP.

Period : 01/01/2010 to 31/06/2011

Employer Name : Crystal Industrial Syndicate Pvt. Ltd.

Location : Mumbai

Designation: QA/QC Engineer

Responsibilities: • Review of PO, Technical data sheets, approved drawings, project specification.

 Preparation of QAP/ITP as per client Technical data sheets & approved drawings.

Inspection of Various and components like forgings, fittings, plates, pipes, machining items & bought out items as per approved drawings with MTC

Copyright: This document is the property of TUV India Pvt. Ltd. and should not be reproduced, except in full without the consent of Tuv Pvt. Ltd. TUV India Private Limited (TÜV NORD GROUP): (REGD. & HEAD OFFICE),



Curriculum Vitae | Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai | Exp. 18 Years and 05 Months

as per respective code requirement.

- Visual and dimensional inspection
- Offering NDT –RT as per approved drawing, defect mapping, attaining repairs as per approved procedures, maintaining joint tracking log.
- Performing test (hydrostatic / pneumatic) with prior verification of calibration certificate.
- Stage and final inspection of fabricated components
- Closing remarks of TPI, and verification of corrective action with documentation
- Preparation of process stage inspection & final documents for release order.
- Worked for Project: Ducting Vietnam Petrochemicals & refinery- TPI ThyssenKrupp industrial solutions Pvt.Ltd.
- Worked on Project: Heat Exchangers Non IBR Equipments-
- Client M/S.Deepak Phenolics-Dahej- Criticality Handled- Detail data & close inspection of Expansion details of Tube To Tube sheet joint 3 no's Equipments prevented from rejection on total lot.



Curriculum Vitae | Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai | Exp. 18 Years and 05 Months

Major Projects / Assignment Handled details:

Item Details	Code / Standard / Specification / MOC	Customer / End Customer / Project Name	Manufacturer Name and Location
ASTM/ASME/IS - A53, A106, A179, A213, A312, A333, A335, A691, API 5L, API 5CT, IS3589, IS 1239- I, EN10255, A192,	L & T / NPCIL RAPP 7 & 8, Toshiba / NTPC, IOCL, EIL, ONGC, BPCL, HPCL, RIL / Jamnagar, Dahej, Hazira, Nagaothane, Thermax / RIL, B & V / RIL,	Seamless/ Welded - Pipes / Tubes	MSL, ISMT, JPL, MLSL, Vibhor Steel, Lalit Pipes, Hindustan Inox, Remi Tubes, Ratnamani, Topworth, Bhushan Steel, Zenith Birla, Nyka Steel, Mukut Tank & Vessel, Yangzau Chengde, Sumitomo, JFE.
ASTM/ASME - B 68, B 75	HDO / NPCIL RAPP 7 & 8,	Copper Tubes	Rajco
ASTM/ASME/IS - A234, A403, A420, IS1239-II	L & T / NPCIL RAPP 7 & 8, RIL / Jamnagar, Dahej, Hazira, Nagaothane,	Pipe Fittings	Longshan, Teekay Tubes, EBY Fittings, CSA Fittings, Navkar Fittings,
ASTM/ASME - A105, A350, A181, A182, A266	RIL / Jamnagar, Dahej, Hazira, Nagaothane, ADCO / CPCL,	Forgings	Supreme Special Steel, Goradia Steel, Paramount Forge,
B16.20, B16.21	RIL, L & T	Gaskets	Teekay, Industrial Engg. Co.,
A193, A194	RIL, L & T	Fasteners	Fast Tech, EBY Fasteners,
A240, A516, A515, IS 2062	RIL, L & T	Plates / Coils	Traders
EN10210, EN10219, IS 2062	RIL, Air Liquide	Structural Sections	Traders
API 610	HPCL, IOCL	Pumps	Arai Pump, Sulzer

Copyright: This document is the property of TUV India Pvt. Ltd. and should not be reproduced, except in full without the consent of Tuv Pvt. Ltd.

TUV India Private Limited (TÜV NORD GROUP): (REGD. & HEAD OFFICE),

801, Raheja Plaza - I, LBS Marg, Ghatkopar (West), Mumbai - 400086, Maharashtra, India.

Tel: + 91 22 66477000, Email: inspection@tuv-nord.com; Website: www.tuv-nord.com/in.



Curriculum Vitae | Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai | Exp. 18 Years and 05 Months

ASME SA-516, SA-240, SA-516 Gr.70 with SS317L cladding & SS-316L /SS317L internals	Reliance, IOCL, L & T, UPL, Technip, HPCL, CCCPL, Gharda Chemical, RCF Limited, EIL, Jubliant, Manali Petrochemical (Chennai).	Pressure vessels / Heat Exchanger	Vijay Tanks & Vessels, Crystal Industrial Pvt Limited, L&T, Raj Engineering, Gemini Engi- Fab,Sudhir Brothers, Novatech, Graphite India Ltd, R. D. Engg, Godrej & Boyce Mfg, Phils Heavy Engg,
Inconel - 625, SS316L, SS317L, SS304	RIL Jamnagar Complex (RCITPL) Qusahwira Field Development Phase-II Project - ADNOC Onshore, Petrofac Emirates LLC EIL, L & T Hydrocarbon Engineering, Baroda / HPCL - Visakh Refinery	Weld Overlay / Cladded Pipes, Fittings & Flanges, Spool	Crystal Industrial Syndicate Pvt. Ltd, Patalganga
Factory capability assessment, Vendor Evaluation, Bid Qualification of factories	As per BID Qualification criteria / client requirement - verification of implementation of ISO standards, Financial statements, manpower availability, plant / plant capability, equipment availability, history of manufacturing, process, facilities, storage, material and document control system etc.	IOCL, BPCL, HPCL,	Pipe Mills: Maharashtra Seamless Limited and Bhushan Steel Limited FRP tank, raw material & Equipment manufacturers

Achievement:

Date	Description
03/02/2023	Work Appreciated by LARSEN & TOUBRO LIMITED(PIPING CENTRE)
02/03/2023	Work Appreciated by M/s. Worley Services India Pvt. Ltd.(31580)
20/02/2018	Received best inspector award in PAN India Competition

Skill Enhancement Trainings Attended:

Date	Hours	Topic
01/02/2024	24	Internal Auditor
01/06/2023	0.08	Road Safety Awareness
10/08/2023	2	EOE PAN India Lessons Learnt - Delhi, Mumbai, Kolkata, Bangalore, Coimbatore
17/08/2023	2	EOE PAN India Lessons Learnt - Delhi, Mumbai, Kolkata, Bangalore, Coimbatore

Copyright: This document is the property of TUV India Pvt. Ltd. and should not be reproduced, except in full without the consent of Tuv Pvt. Ltd.

TUV India Private Limited (TÜV NORD GROUP): (REGD. & HEAD OFFICE),

801, Raheja Plaza - I, LBS Marg, Ghatkopar (West), Mumbai - 400086, Maharashtra, India.

Tel: + 91 22 66477000, Email: inspection@tuv-nord.com; Website: www.tuv-nord.com/in.



Curriculum Vitae | Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai | Exp. 18 Years and 05 Months

05/09/2023	2	EOE PAN India Lessons Learnt - Delhi, Mumbai, Kolkata, Bangalore, Coimbatore
28/12/2023	2	EOE PAN India Lessons Learnt - Delhi and Ahmedabad



Curriculum Vitae | Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Manager - QHSE, Inspection Services, Mumbai | Exp. 18 Years and 05 Months

Personal information:

Name : Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Date of Birth : 15/05/1985

Age : 38 Years and 09 Months

Nationality : Indian

Location : Mumbai

Gender : Male

Languages : Hindi ,English ,Marathi

: Married

TUV India DOJ : 11/07/2011

Exp. with TUV India : 12 Years and 08 Months

Total Experience : 18 Years and 05 Months

Declaration:

Marital Status

I hearby decalre that the information provided above is true and accurate to the best of my knowledge.

Shrikant Ramesh Patil

Downloaded on: 23/02/2024

----End----